CYNTHIA I. DICKSON

I'm a **front-end software engineer** with almost 3 years of experience in the software industry. For the past few years, my focus area has been front-end development with VueJS. I am very design-conscious because I spent the early stages in design roles.

Lagos, Nigeria +234-806-368-5147 cynthiaiboro@gmail.com github.com/cynthiaiboro

EXPERIENCE

THE BULB AFRICA, Lagos, Nigeria — Frontend Developer AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

Produce, modify, and maintain web application user interfaces. Work with Data Scientists and backend engineers – collaborating on APIs, data structure, and data integration. Maintain software workflow, versioning, and testing during development and address any bugs.

Document all code according to common development best practices and create technical documentation of project work to facilitate knowledge sharing.

ENOV8 SOLUTIONS, Lagos, Nigeria — Frontend Developer

FEBRUARY 2020 - AUGUST 2020

Translated designs and wireframes into high quality code Built reusable components using Vue concepts.

Optimized components for maximum performance across a vast array of web-capable devices and browsers

Consumed restful APIs

JIGGLE NIGERIA, Uyo, Nigeria — Frontend Developer

JANUARY 2019 - JANUARY 2020

Built product to match design and specified requirements. Ensured compatibility across multiple devices and operating systems.

Maintained, debugged and fixed issues that arise in your product.

RESPONSIBILITIES

UI designs to code Responsive Design **API** integration State Management Payment gateway integration Integration of ticketing and support solutions. Postman, Swagger to test endpoints Git Docker Authentication (JWT, Passport) Authorization and permissions

TOOLS

Graph Integration

QR Code Integration

Cloudinary, AWS S3.

HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind Css, Bootstrap, Element UI, Materialize CSS, LESS, SASS, JavaScript, JQuery, VueJS, NUXT JS, React JS, Vuepress, VueX HNG, Remote — Fellowship program MARCH 2019

Design tools - Figma, Adobe XD

MY PORTFOLIO

Here a link to a few projects I've worked on

https://cynthia-dickson.netlify.app/

PROJECT TRACKING TOOLS

Code Versioning GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket

Project Management Jira, Trello, Airtable, Asana

Communication Slack, Microsoft Teams, Google Meet

EDUCATION

University of Port Harcourt, Port Harcourt - B.Sc

January 2014 - June 2018 Computer Science

Aladumo International High School, Port Harcourt - Waec

September 2006 - June 2012

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

ExpressWebJS — View

A Node FrameWork with expressive and organised syntax.

I handled versioned documentation with VuePress.

SOFT SKILLS

Communication,
Teamwork, Leadership,
Attention to details,
Organization and
planning.

REFERENCES

Available on request